[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f36", "question": "What epic poem begins \"Arma virumque cano\"?", "answer": "The Aeneid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb12065ff7d326b622a66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Curium?", "answer": "Cm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b178", "question": "When did the Sydney Opera House officially open its doors to the public?", "answer": "20 October 1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c720fbde8045e48466be", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is the closest to Earth in size?", "answer": "Venus -- The two planets are nearly identical in size and mass, with Venus measuring at about 0.95 the size of Earth.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb01", "question": "The Nintendo character we know as Mario first appeared in what arcade game?", "answer": "Donkey Kong", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c299", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52f", "question": "What plant is rum made from?", "answer": "Sugar cane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81d04d0de9af39e9d468a", "question": "Why was 46 B.C.E. called the \"year of confusion\"?", "answer": "It had two extra months", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa77173838c5c8a417f38", "question": "What are people who love eating ice called?", "answer": "Pagophagiacs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a952561d1b4d384d5d675", "question": "What are \"Castanets\"?", "answer": "A type of musical instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba2", "question": "What city is the setting for the TV series \"Mad Men\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c0", "question": "What legendary actress was nicknamed \"The Face\"?", "answer": "Greta Garbo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37c", "question": "Who was the 15th President of the US?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a536", "question": "What mountain chain runs from Maine to Alabama?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af983c3aeb0982ee4559549", "question": "In the movie \"Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens\", who kills Han Solo?", "answer": "Kylo Ren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69c6f20565ad31a57c76c", "question": "The \"Era of Good Feelings\" is associated with the administration of which president?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f2f96682715b82711cef", "question": "What is Joseph Priestley credited with discovering?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70e", "question": "What does \"Meri Kurisumasu\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Merry Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76ffceec85e375820b2f2", "question": "In which city was the 2000 movie \"Gladiator\" filmed?", "answer": "Ouarzazate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3b5eff048f679a45ab34", "question": "A group of tigers is called what?", "answer": "An ambush", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7be16877e98cb9777895c", "question": "What country occupies the southern end of the Arabian Peninsula?", "answer": "Yemen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c008", "question": "In 1946, Yvon Petra was the last Wimbledon champion to do what?", "answer": "Wear trousers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396af", "question": "What actor founded the Purple Rose Theater Company in Michigan?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d06", "question": "In what 1949 novel is the world divided into three principal continents: Oceania, Eurasia, Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c47", "question": "What ventriloquist was best known for his dummy Charlie McCarthy?", "answer": "Edgar Bergen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac86", "question": "What country gave the Statue of Liberty to the US?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3235b4bf195a31e15d73b2", "question": "What is a system of circulating ocean currents referred to as?", "answer": "A Gyre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b844364247bf200fb87e", "question": "What year did Valve release the Steam platform?", "answer": "2003", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7704eeec85e375820b2f7", "question": "What republic claims to be the world's oldest surviving republic?", "answer": "San Marino", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3deaff048f679a45ab56", "question": "What is the only moon in the solar system that has an atmosphere?", "answer": "Titan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe771daeec85e375820b301", "question": "Which U.S. state has a town named after a game show?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9ba95364247bf200fb899", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death or dead bodies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbec", "question": "What year saw Jean Paul Gaultier's first individual collection for men?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a864", "question": "What is the literal translation of Montenegro's name?", "answer": "Black mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f4", "question": "What Mojave Desert city has a name meaning \"the meadows\" in Spanish?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e1", "question": "What is the name of the bar that Homer Simpson frequents?", "answer": "Moe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab96cb86faa38a764be524", "question": "Which car company did Christian von Koenigsegg found in 1994?", "answer": "Koenigsegg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a62a32ebb971c1417fb91", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ff", "question": "What was the name of the club in Liverpool made famous for the Beatles early appearances?", "answer": "The Cavern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd2", "question": "Who were the first people to separate copper from its ore?", "answer": "The Ancient Egyptians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca34", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7505a9e54d890926f702", "question": "What is illegal to eat with a cherry pie in Kansas?", "answer": "Ice cream", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b624", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by a bull?", "answer": "Taurus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339490", "question": "Anthony Hopkins played a ventriloquist in which 1978 movie?", "answer": "Magic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b801", "question": "How old is a Jewish boy who has a bar mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a103", "question": "Directed by Sydney Pollack, which film won the Oscar for Best Picture in 1986?", "answer": "Out of Africa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c89ff04d658268c9317", "question": "Who served as the Minister of Armaments and War Production in Nazi Germany during most of World War II.", "answer": "Albert Speer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04f", "question": "What was the only James Bond film to crack the top-ten list for highest grossing movies of the 1960s?", "answer": "Thunderball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96627ccba3ffe45786ec", "question": "In which European country is Tokaj wine produced?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded077ea2747c8aff16d28", "question": "Ireland's River Shannon flows into which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c8", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e1", "question": "The islands called Islas Malvinas by the Argentinians are referred to by what name by the British?", "answer": "The Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339039", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbbd", "question": "What is converted into alcohol during brewing?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e95db7ccba3ffe45786e5", "question": "What do koala bears dine on?", "answer": "Eucalyptus leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4ddd206d333868d34d709", "question": "Besides \"Axis Sally\", who was another famous propaganda broadcaster for the Nazis?", "answer": "Berlin Betty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede5006ce05a3942286de4", "question": "What were George Harrison's names in the Traveling Wilburys?", "answer": "Nelson and Spike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6902b42d4a3561a9f05", "question": "What 2010 horror novel by Jeff Strand was nominated for a Bram Stoker Award?", "answer": "Dweller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa23", "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa3", "question": "What do the Plastics call their \"slam book\" in the 2004 movie \"Mean Girls\"?", "answer": "The Burn Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b450", "question": "The US was among several nations that sent troops to quell which 1900 uprising in China?", "answer": "The Boxer Rebellion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf01", "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?", "answer": "Sangria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be3", "question": "In what year was actor Johnny Depp born?", "answer": "1963", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f64f6f5f79087132fb43", "question": "Which actress who played Alia Atreides in 1984's \"Dune\" and went on to star in 1998's \"Urban Legend\"?", "answer": "Alicia Witt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe446ce05a3942286eeb", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon,\" Hannibal Lector speculates Will Graham is wearing what brand of shaving lotion?", "answer": "Old Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d96", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d7", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbd", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in Black Forest cake?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43d", "question": "Where do people traditionally dance the flamenco?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9f", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess to execute a castling maneuver?", "answer": "King and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a65cc9a45431f553a9cce", "question": "What is the name of the exclusive bar above the \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" within Disneyland?", "answer": "Club 33", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c3", "question": "What late 19\u00ad60's pop singer was backed by a group called the Union Gap?", "answer": "Gary Puckett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b859", "question": "How many rings are there on the Olympic flag?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb0877e98cb97778a51", "question": "What does Machu Picchu translate to in English?", "answer": "Old mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f80301dd7bf43be5e83c", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd3eb7e83c707845b2157", "question": "Red had how many parole hearings through out the course of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c7e20775fa611bce67dd", "question": "Why do penny loafers have a slot for a coin?", "answer": "For a payphone -- Penny loafers allowed schoolchildren to always have two pennies if they needed to make an emergency call home.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c7", "question": "What is the Latin name for a guinea pig?", "answer": "Caviaprocellus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b3", "question": "In what city can tourists visit the famous Bourbon Street?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac29", "question": "Which European city is served by Galileo Galilei Airport?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b703", "question": "What is an albatross in golf scoring?", "answer": "3 under par", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3b", "question": "What book was written as a sequel to \"The Adventures of Tom Sawyer\"?", "answer": "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8d", "question": "What did Teleworld, Inc. rename itself in 1999, after its flagship product?", "answer": "TiVo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde519ec6c6b019850c9a90", "question": "Herbert Hoover became well known when he organized relief efforts for what country after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a37", "question": "Who recorded the multi-platinum 1970s album \"Bat Out of Hell\"?", "answer": "Meat Loaf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f56", "question": "In one myth, what dance was first performed by Hi'iaka to appease the volcano goddess, Pele?", "answer": "The hula", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a1", "question": "What is the literal translation of the condition known as \"diprosopus\"?", "answer": "Two-faced", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be75", "question": "What NBA star was known for his signature spin move, the Dream Shake?", "answer": "Hakeem Olajuwon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08925cf631c2414a13b5e", "question": "What MTV music show premiered on September 14, 1998?", "answer": "Total Request Live (TRL)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adcc", "question": "Which British liner did a German U-boat sink on May 7th 1915?", "answer": "RMS Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ca", "question": "In what US state was Abraham Lincoln born?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93aaf6bd93ce3a4e5f699", "question": "What science combines computer science, statistics, engineering, and biology?", "answer": "Bioinformatics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cce3877e98cb97778a2e", "question": "Which country is known by its inhabitants as Suomi?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f3", "question": "On what continent were the Boer Wars fought?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7a", "question": "What scandal forced US President Richard Nixon to resign in 1974?", "answer": "Watergate Scandal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42e", "question": "Which ocean is between South America and Africa?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8a99901dd7bf43be5e750", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what did the cat take?", "answer": "The rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae866977f28483af1e7fdd4", "question": "What is the name of the musician best known for his 1993 song \"What is Love\"?", "answer": "Haddaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71d", "question": "What is a tanager?", "answer": "A bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdc38e347d002c297e4e5", "question": "In which film did Madonna play a character called \"Gloria Tatlock\"?", "answer": "Shanghai Surprise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa55c73838c5c8a417f24", "question": "Which creatures produce gossamer?", "answer": "Spiders", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1687cf7c52aae91cc07c8", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338968", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was arachnophobic?", "answer": "Little Miss Muffet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dc", "question": "As punishment for not appreciating Apollo's music, King Midas's ears were transformed into the ears of what animal?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51c", "question": "What is Whisky distilled from?", "answer": "Fermented grain mash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97e", "question": "Mount Sunflower is what US state's highest point?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc3", "question": "Who was dipped by the heel in the River Styx to give him invulnerability?", "answer": "Achilles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008851cf842fa4c4ba9688", "question": "In which country is the Commandaria wine region?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff6", "question": "What is Johnny Chase's nickname on the TV show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Drama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba93", "question": "In a standard deck of cards, the Jack, Queen, and King all show both eyes in what suit?", "answer": "Clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cd", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32d", "question": "What does TNT stand for?", "answer": "Trinitrotoluene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe12e58e39efa6330e0fed2", "question": "Which US state has the most lighthouses?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c028", "question": "What does \"shogun\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "Military commander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c669", "question": "Who developed the light bulb while working in his Menlo Park laboratory?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a769", "question": "In terms of area, what is the largest borough in New York City?", "answer": "Queens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe734c9eec85e375820b23c", "question": "Who chaired the \"Wannsee Conference\" during World War II?", "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fb", "question": "Who were the two founders of the company \"Hewlett-Packard\"?", "answer": "Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7b1bff048f679a45abf2", "question": "Where are carpal bones found?", "answer": "Wrist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5967613d2b59efe0e9417ea2", "question": "The song \"Good Girl\" was the 12th Top 20 hit for what artist?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc56f6ce05a3942286f3e", "question": "What 19th century opera singer was known as the \"Swedish Nightingale\"?", "answer": "Jenny Lind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a4b720565ad31a57c7c1", "question": "Who was the last US president from the Whig Party?", "answer": "Millard Fillmore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e3", "question": "How many items are in a gross?", "answer": "144", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e95487ccba3ffe45786dd", "question": "What country are you most likely to hear its residents speak Malagasy?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3c", "question": "Approximately, how tall is the Leaning Tower of Pisa?", "answer": "56 m", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338950", "question": "What Mozart opera focuses on fiancee swapping as its theme?", "answer": "Cosi fan tutte", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600242ee4be4723ccac2218f", "question": "In Jane Austen\u2019s \"Pride and Prejudice\", what is the name of the pompous clergyman who marries Elizabeth\u2019s sister, Charlotte?", "answer": "Mr. Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3e", "question": "The \"Pentagon Papers\" contained secret government information about what?", "answer": "The Vietnam War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b153", "question": "On Christmas Day 800 A.D., who was coronated as emperor of the Holy Roman Empire?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59d185103b17032616b590fc", "question": "What century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "1370", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50c", "question": "What chessman makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "The knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c35e89a6b7193fa56721f83", "question": "How many strings are on a baritone ukulele?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ca", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of Kirk Van Houten's demo singing tape?", "answer": "Can I Borrow a Feeling?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b8c20565ad31a57c760", "question": "What president turned down a scholarship to Harvard?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049c00cf93664eb10486a3", "question": "Art Spiegelman is best known for his creation of which graphic novel?", "answer": "Maus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f17804eb8195c09b948d5c0", "question": "What are the suction-like cups on a gecko's toes that allows it to attach itself to any surface called?", "answer": "Setae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3a", "question": "Thomas Jefferson is depicted on what US coin?", "answer": "5 cent coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ef", "question": "Which singer sang \"I Believe In Father Christmas''?", "answer": "Greg Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c67", "question": "Who directed the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "John Badham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1da", "question": "Before his ears were cut off in 1990 by a political rival, what nation was ruled by dictator Samuel Doe?", "answer": "Liberia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde6", "question": "What floor number is often skipped in Chinese buildings, as the thirteenth is in the West?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f2", "question": "How many episodes of \u201cMagnum P.I.\u201d were made?", "answer": "162", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d99a508b8581f80b092b6", "question": "What highly awaited Japanese hot hatchback went on sale around the world in 2017?", "answer": "Honda Civic Type R", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b293", "question": "What European country ruled Macau until December 20, 1999?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf3", "question": "What year saw the release of the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e6", "question": "Which US president lived in Shadow Lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a703", "question": "Which is the smallest state in the US?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea49feff048f679a45abbf", "question": "When blood becomes more acid than normal, what it is the condition called?", "answer": "Acidosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b787364247bf200fb873", "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "The Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b4", "question": "In Greek mythology what is the place of ideal happiness called?", "answer": "Elysium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5c0d5dad637d903c881d", "question": "What is Valentine's Day referred to as in Finland?", "answer": "\"Friend's Day\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa28", "question": "A statue of Billy Bremner stands outside the ground of which football stadium?", "answer": "Leeds United", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b5", "question": "What is 1 knot of speed equivalent to?", "answer": "1 Nautical Mile per Hour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e828fe83fe1f2a824bd9", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73c", "question": "What part of the body is affected by tinnitus?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339923", "question": "What was the name of the high school in the movie \u201cGrease\u201d?", "answer": "Rydell High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea344fff048f679a45aaf6", "question": "What do plants produce through photosynthesis?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a7", "question": "What two actors exchanged faces in the 1997 movie \"Face/Off\"?", "answer": "Nicholas Cage and John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2d", "question": "What was Mark Twain's real name?", "answer": "Samuel Clemens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b43eec85e375820b2bf", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s longest train tunnel?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8aac301dd7bf43be5e760", "question": "Nephelococcygia is the practice of doing what?", "answer": "Finding shapes in clouds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949e", "question": "Who wrote the novel the miniseries \"Shogun\" was based on?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec722ea57c9fcac0ce71978", "question": "In what city is the Kentucky Derby held?", "answer": "Louisville", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db77bc0ab2c8f322317fee", "question": "Which holiday did Canada Day replace in 1982?", "answer": "Dominion Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8d", "question": "In what year did Babe Ruth reach 500 career home runs?", "answer": "1929", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8f", "question": "Who invented nylon?", "answer": "Wallace Carothers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b836", "question": "What is the diameter of a basketball hoop?", "answer": "18 inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e3", "question": "What is the most common ending for a city, town, village or hamlet in England?", "answer": "-ton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a1", "question": "What is the largest of the islands off the southern coast of Cape Cod?", "answer": "Martha's Vineyard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9cc", "question": "In which modern day country would you find the region known as Transylvania?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5658733a95c66dc4fe759", "question": "Which number system uses only the symbols 1 and 0?", "answer": "The binary system", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db75050ab2c8f322317fe3", "question": "On which coast would you find the smallest Canadian province?", "answer": "East coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592ead5df83302ff91e4647b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5efa9450ccb363a2cbc52279", "question": "When did the Japanese attack Pearl Harbor? ", "answer": "December 7, 1941", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbc90ec60f0007efaba0e55", "question": "Dr. Jonathan Crane is the real name of which DC Comics supervillain?", "answer": "Scarecrow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9045301dd7bf43be5e874", "question": "Which Thanksgiving favorite spawned the invention of the TV dinner?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b0ea3b964118b2bb3809cf", "question": "What year did the \"ILOVEYOU\" virus began infecting computers worldwide?", "answer": "2000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcde", "question": "According to the Bible, what is now guarded by an angel holding a flaming sword?", "answer": "The Garden of Eden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a61ca2ebb971c1417fb8a", "question": "By what name is \"One Thousand and One Nights\" better known as in the English language?", "answer": "Arabian Nights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bac", "question": "Which two dimensional character issued these orders, \"Off with her head\"?", "answer": "The Queen of Hearts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338946", "question": "Which singer's 2000 autobiography \"Chasing Down the Dawn\" detailed her life growing up in Alaska?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a551d83e1c6f9840ba3190", "question": "What is a \"Pickelhaube\"?", "answer": "A spiked German helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd660f8a5bfecdd737e0839", "question": "Where did the tradition of pumpkin carving originate?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33a", "question": "If you suffer from phobophobia, what do you fear?", "answer": "Phobias", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c3", "question": "What company was formerly known as the \"Computing-Tabulating-Recording Company\"?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ebd406d333868d34d75f", "question": "To whom was the first .com internet domain registered?", "answer": "Symbolics.com", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d09", "question": "What author was still an English teacher at Maine's Hampden Academy when his first book was published?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c060", "question": "What are the three colors of the flag of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Red, White and Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e4", "question": "Which country originated opera?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad6", "question": "In which continent would you find the Lena River?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a1e1d47b5a031299b745739", "question": "During which century did Norsemen discover and settle in Greenland?", "answer": "10th Century", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd58", "question": "The Turing Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Computer science", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c205", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa7", "question": "What actress starred simultaneously on \"Dynasty\" and \"T.J. Hooker\" during the  early 1980s?", "answer": "Heather Locklear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe258b0658e585fda9cfa40", "question": "What type of sugar typically includes a small amount of cornstarch to prevent lumping while mixing?", "answer": "Powdered sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5d", "question": "What year was the first pair of stereo headphones produced?", "answer": "1943", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af50", "question": "What happened on September 1, 1939 that led to Britain and France declaring war on Germany?", "answer": "Invasion of Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart of Darkness,\" what does Bart break?", "answer": "His leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfac", "question": "Kainolophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Novelty, or new", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c7a469bb8041d07a051", "question": "What is \"Ajiaco\"?", "answer": "A type of chicken soup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c774", "question": "What animal species name is slang for the mechanics profession?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5bea5dad637d903c881c", "question": "Which country observes an official Vernal Equinox Day?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339777", "question": "Why must Leonard tattoo notes on himself and take polaroids in the film \"Memento\"?", "answer": "He has no short-term memory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d5", "question": "Speed Skating originated in which part of the world?", "answer": "Scandinavia and Northern Europe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5952427f736d4be723796b64", "question": "How old was Ruby Bridges on her first day at her new school in Louisiana?", "answer": "6 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb2d37e83c707845b2114", "question": "HIV stands for what?", "answer": "Human Immunodeficiency Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccd25ec223966ae8f88a9", "question": "Who was the first Disney princess with a tattoo?", "answer": "Pocahontas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4b", "question": "Eric Arthur Blair was the real name of which author?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa50", "question": "What is the capital of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines?", "answer": "Kingstown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f4c6ff048f679a45aacb", "question": "Lockiophobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Childbirth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76f54eec85e375820b2e7", "question": "Where can you find the iconic Apollo Theater?", "answer": "Harlem, New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37b", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c5ac9d816e292245c2b", "question": "What element was removed from Leonardo da Vinci's The Last Supper by careless workers?", "answer": "While installing a doorway in the wall that holds\u00a0\"The Last Supper\", builders cut into the mural, lopping off\u00a0Jesus' feet.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57cc15415ba52ed6f0aa4", "question": "Who is the boss on NBC's TV Show \"The Office\"?", "answer": "Michael Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd77877e98cb97778a37", "question": "Which Canadian island is famously known for its mussels?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e3f4135cb9e8bda6821366", "question": "By what other name is the folk tale \"Cinderella\" also known as?", "answer": "The Little Glass Slipper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392cd", "question": "What 2001 thriller starred Halle Berry, John Travolta, and Hugh Jackman?", "answer": "Swordfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf49", "question": "What is the next-to-last event?", "answer": "Penultimate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4da3c6c6b019850c9a82", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c755", "question": "What is the opposite of insulin and secreted by the pancreas?", "answer": "Glucagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2dc", "question": "Who was Arthur Jefferson's comedy partner?", "answer": "Oliver Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdc66e347d002c297e4e7", "question": "Which year was the film \"Shanghai Surprise\", starring Madonna and Sean Penn, released in?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d06d3a870e6f05ba600857", "question": "Secretary birds are native to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339040", "question": "Who wrote a book entitled \"The Adventures of Lord Iffy Boatrace\"?", "answer": "Bruce Dickinson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971df3a89261e916c8e09a7", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11f", "question": "The first significant gold rush in the US occurred in what state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e910215d7247dfc0fa00310", "question": "At what speed do massless particles travel in vacuum?", "answer": "Speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596760e52b59efe0e9417e9f", "question": "Panophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Everything", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b797", "question": "What wax sculptor made the death mask of Marie Antoinette?", "answer": "Madame Tussaud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95abb855722f97b22684d3", "question": "What is the name of Han Solo\u2019s ship?", "answer": "Millennium Falcon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b006", "question": "What war gave the US its freedom from Britain?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fe", "question": "In which movie did Eddie Murphy play a character named Prince Akeem?", "answer": "Coming to America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf1", "question": "Who wrote \"Slaughterhouse Five\"?", "answer": "Kurt Vonnegut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f79", "question": "In music what is meant by \"pianissimo\"?", "answer": "Very soft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590722c63745b36be7303a02", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the song \"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc75", "question": "What year were Reese's Peanut Butter Cups first introduced to the US market?", "answer": "1928", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a0", "question": "In what state was the TV show \"B.J. and Bear\" set?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba1", "question": "What is the name for the fingers of a fork?", "answer": "Tines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25da6b63e5727cf5a4867", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the single \"All I Want For Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99c", "question": "Completed in 1911, what dam was built across the Salt River near Phoenix?", "answer": "Roosevelt Dam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd49cd00d154d7af00b8cb", "question": "What year did Nirvana frontman, Kurt Cobain, die?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82b", "question": "Pancetta is derived from the meat of what animal?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "general"}]